# Miguel Mejía

Visual communicator and front-end developer

info@mmejia.com mmejia.com cv.mmejia.com (+57) 304 383 9127 Bogotá, Colombia

I am a visual communicator with over 10 years of experience working on a spectrum that ranges from visual communication and research to front-end web development. My purpose is to support the role of the communications and technologies in building more inclusive societies.

## **Experience**

Amazink Studio June 2020 - October 2023
Communications and Technology Director
Lead the conceptualization of projects and the development of new products. I researched and processed information provided by clients, created narratives and wrote the final information for editorial, digital and audiovisual projects. I structured and implemented the studio's project management platform. I performed the coding for the digital projects.

mmejia.com July 2014 - Current

Photographer and visual communicator

Developed and produced photographic and drawing narratives for projects related to culture, work, education, reinsertion and access to information.

**Abstraer estrategias** March 2012 - July 2014 **Creative Director** 

Created and developed visual concepts for food products. Lead branding and typographic development projects.

#### Skills

I work with fluency and empathy on issues such as accessibility, human and labor rights, gender and sexual orientation, climate change, culture and armed conflict.

I conceptualize, plan and develop strategies, design systems, communication plans and toolkits.

I have advanced knowledge in photography and video, Photoshop, Capture One, Illustrator, InDesign and DaVinciResolve.

I code with HTML, CSS, JavaScript. I use GIT and deploy sites in Jekyll, 11ty and WordPress.

I constantly engage in learning and training processes.

I can approach projects from the research and framing of the information to the creation of narratives, the formulation of strategies and the production of communicational tools.

#### Referencias

**Sandra Osorio** (+57) 319 223 8143 Communications dDirector in Ekuanima

**Manuel Rodríguez** (+57) 316 436 8063 Evaluation and knowledge leader at CreativeLab

**César Gutierrez** (+57) 300 313 1331 Graphic designer in Humboldt institute

### Educación

Universidad Nacional de Colombia Graphic Design 2005 - 2010 (unfinished)

Pontificia Universidad Javeriana Industrial Design 2001 - 2003 (unfinished)



# Miguel Mejía

Comunicador visual y desarrollador front-end

info@mmejia.com mmejia.com cv.mmejia.com (+57) 304 383 9127 Bogotá, Colombia

Soy un comunicador visual con más de 10 años de experiencia que trabaja en un espectro que va desde la comunicación visual y la investigación hasta el desarrollo web front-end. Mi propósito es apoyar el papel de la comunicación y la tecnología en la construcción de sociedades más inclusivas.

## Experiencia laboral

Amazink Studio Junio 2020 - Octubre 2023
Director de comunicaciones y tecnología
Lideré la conceptualización de proyectos y el
desarrollo de nuevos productos. Investigué y
procesé la información entregada por
clientes, creé las narrativas y redacté la
información final de los proyectos
editoriales, digitales y audiovisuales.
Estructuré e implementé la plataforma para
la gestión de proyectos del estudio. Realicé
la programación para los proyectos digitales.

mmejia.com Julio 2014 - Actualidad Fotógrafo y comunicador visual

Desarrollé y produje narrativas desde la fotografía y el dibujo para proyectos relacionados con cultura, trabajo, educación, reincorporación y acceso a la información.

**Abstraer estrategias** Marzo 2012 - Julio 2014 **Director Creativo** 

Creé y desarrollé conceptos visuales para productos alimenticios. Dirigí los proyectos de creación de marca y desarrollo tipográfico.

### **Habilidades**

Trabajo con fluidez y empatía temas como accesibilidad, derechos humanos y laborales, género y diversidad sexual, cambio climático, cultura y conflicto armado.

Conceptualizo, planeo y desarrollo estrategias, sistemas de diseño, planes de comunicacion y herramientas de trabajo.

Tengo conocimientos avanzados en fotografía y video, Photoshop, Capture One, Illustrator, InDesign y DaVinciResolve.

Programo en HTML, CSS, JavaScript. Uso GIT y despliego sitios en Jekyll, 11ty y WordPress.

Participo constantemente en procesos de aprendizaje y capacitación.

Puedo abordar proyectos desde la investigación y estructuración de la información hasta la creación de narrativas, el desarrollo de estrategias y la producción de herramientas visuales para su difusión.

### Referencias

**Sandra Osorio** (+57) 319 223 8143 Directora de comunicaciones en Ekuanima

*Manuel Rodríguez* (+57) 316 436 8063 Líder de evaluación y conocimiento en CreativeLab

**César Gutierrez** (+57) 300 313 1331 Diseñador gráfico en el Instituto Humboldt

### Educación

Universidad Nacional de Colombia Diseño Gráfico 2005 - 2010 (Sin finalizar)

Pontificia Universidad Javeriana Diseño Industrial 2001 - 2003 (Sin finalizar)

